Welcome, everyone, to the complete intro to Vue 3.
My name is Ben Hong, and I'm excited to spend the next couple days with you
as we go over the fundamentals of view and just get you all set up
so that you feel confident trying out view for your next project.
All right, so as far as a little bit of a welcome,
a little fun fact I usually like to use is I'm a big fan of amusement park rides.
So this is the one from Orlando Universal Studios.
And so the one I really want to get up, though, is if you ever go to Disneyland,
check out the, because this is the classic Jurassic Park one.
They've redone the one in Disneyland to be the Jurassic World theme.
And so they've done a lot of really cool 3D effects and stuff.
Highly, highly recommend it.
If you're having trouble finding me in the back, there I am raising my arms up there.
But with that aside, a little bit about me.
I'm a senior staff developer experience engineer at Netlify,
a Vue.js core team member, Nux ambassador, Vue master instructor,
and I'm a Google developer expert in web technologies as well as the MAT platform.
All right, so if you're wondering who this workshop is for,
this workshop, because this is a complete intro to Vue,
covers people looking to get started with their first JavaScript framework
for basically building web user interfaces.
All the way to people who are looking to either learn about what makes Vue special
and really gain the skills necessary so that if they want to try using Vue on their next project,
they are certainly more than welcome to.
And of course, everyone in between.
So let's say we have a good gamut here of different experiences.
And so yeah, hope to cover all that in this workshop today.
All right, so a couple of things to know about this workshop.
Some things you probably want to know if you're watching this and as far as like,
we'll call it prerequisites, is basically if you have some familiarity with HTML,
CSS, and JavaScript.
So in other words, you don't need to be an expert in any of these fields.
I designed it so that as long as you have the fundamentals for each of these,
you'll be set to go.
Familiarity with the code editor is also super helpful,
as we'll be doing a lot of coding in this workshop.
Because after all, while there's a lot of theoretical things to talk about,
I want to get you all hands-on experience working with Vue to see how it feels
when you're taking it for a test run.
The code editor I'll be using is VS Code.
And I recommend that one because the extensions that we'll be using also are in VS Code by default.
And so if you can't follow along with that, that'd be great.
But otherwise, no worries if you want to use whatever code editor that you prefer.
We'll also be doing a little bit with the terminal as well,
because as most of you know, when it comes to frameworks,
build tools are a pretty big thing.
So as you have some familiarity running some basic commands,
that'll be useful as well.
In addition, we'll be also using browser dev tools.
So I'll be using Chrome in this instance.
But whether it's Firefox or whatever your preferred browser of choice is,
basically we'll be inside of there inspecting stuff and looking at how everything's working.
And finally, basic knowledge of Git and MPM would be great as well,
because all of the resources are going to be basically encapsulated in the repo that I have.
And then we'll be installing the dependencies with MPM.
So just as long as you've had some basic exposure to that,
you should be good to go for this workshop.
All right, and so the promised resource,
everything is going to be living at this repo, which is github.com,
slash Ben Code Zen, and then slash complete intro to View 3 Workshop.
So if you just go to slash Ben Code Zen and Repos, you should see it at the very top.
And if it looks a little barren in there, don't worry,
we're going to be populating it as we go throughout the workshop.
All right, as far as what you can expect from the workshop,
I'm a big fan of the workshop format of learn, question, and apply.
So basically, we'll be going through the process of starting with the learn step,
which is every time we have a new concept,
we'll be going through explanations and examples,
so you can start getting exposed to what's going on.
Then there'll always be opportunities to ask questions.
So if any clarifications, what ifs, that's a great time to kind of get in there
to start engaging with the material.
And finally, arguably the most important step in my mind is that we go ahead and
apply what we just learned.
So there'll be lots of opportunity to do exercises.
And most importantly, I encourage you to play and experiment with it.
I'll provide some guidance regarding some things you can do with the exercise.
But the more you kind of get into it and play around with it,
the sicker it'll be for you when it comes to learning it.
And finally, even though we're here talking about View,
an important thing to remember is that all code is compromised.
So earlier we heard from people coming from different frameworks.
Different frameworks have made different choices and trade-offs along the way as
their authors sort of created those things.
So just know that whatever my opinion is, I encourage you to question and
or disagree with it, because after all, your opinion and experience matters.
At the end of the day,
the most important thing is that you choose what's best for
you and your team in order to serve your customers.